Hi, and this was some I want to do an overview of cascade interface. The cascade is
chart you see in the sidebar and there are a few options how to use chart in
Windsor. So first it's a sidebar option. You can do it on and off with this icon. So it's
you can have continuous chart conversation in separate view.
You also know we can use command. It's an inline chart if you click command + i and
control + i on Windows Linux. So you can use a chart exactly in some place in your code.
Okay, let's now talk what options or controls you have right here. We have right here
as a chat mode. We'll cover them in separate lesson. So I will explain it in details like
a chart and write mode. What is it? What's the best use cases?
Now let's talk about the chat models. If you click right here, you will see the dropdown
with chat models. And there are a list of models you can use. Right here are some
models of faster property tasks while others work better for planning and reasoning.
You can change the model when served use by default. Of course, the list of models which
are available for you may vary on your subscription and may change all the time. From nice
features, so you can use the group. If you click, you can group models by provider. For
the risk of all models and open AI, you can click show all. You see all the models,
GPT file is now available, and traffic, Google models, XCI, DeepSeek and other. You can
also sort them on groups and by cost. Like you will see is it okay as a premium models
and how much they cost. There are other models, there is also the cost and there are
BYO key models, it's the models which require you will provide your own API key. So you
want to use them. And there are some free models. When I was GPT file is also free, but
I don't see it before a long time, it might be for some preview purposes. But for example,
there are free models from wind serve SWE, a light version in the normal one, so you
can use them for free and DeepSeek as well. But it might change over time. And also you
can search by model like, you know, I want to use some SWE light, for example. You can
also have a field to submit a chat prompt. So you can make requests with a natural language
like you can use like, I want you to create me, you know, the calculator with the functions
of and say the least of functions you want to. So this is close to the natural language.
You can ask questions about your code, get a suggestion in this chat interface, edit across
multiple files, you use some tools. You can also move some files right here into the
chat. So it will be mentioned here. What else? Some chat responses, main code, markup, text,
code blocks like you see right here. It also might include the terminal commands, when
some messages like it reads the terminal, it analyzes some files and etc. So also the
recent night option about adding a context with, when you mentioned something, but
you'll cover it in separate lesson and to go into tales. For example, also important
to write a good prompts. And in one of my video in the beginning of this course, which
name is popular use cases, or for developers, I provided prompt examples, what you can
use, so to get better responses. Also, pay attention how your prompt is clear to AI.
Now let's talk about some chat history. For example, you can undo changes made by cascade
it anytime. So for example, if you scroll up, like you can find any of your prompt you
written, when you hover on it, you will have a reward button when you click on it, you
can confirm any of your changes will be reverted to this particular step. But please be
aware that reverse can be undone, so use them really carefully. Of course, you can find
all your changes. If you hover on a site, you see the small lines right here. If you click
on one of them, you will have a pop up with the changes you have. And when you hover,
you see the time, you see the message of your prompt. And when you scroll down, like you
hover on others, so you will see the rest. So you can click on them and see them in the
chat. For example, you can also, I cannot click, so you can just close it. Okay. So now
you know, you can restore your code. What about chat history? You can click right here
on a pass conversations and to see all the charts you had before. Also, when you click,
let me close it. When you also, when you click on this dropdown with the chat name,
you also will see the chat history. So you can click the all conversations or see on the
active conversations. For example, what else, you can click on, pardon you, conversation.
I recommend you to do it for any new questions like you have. If you don't need a context
because when you send multiple messages in a wind source cascade, it remembers the whole conversation
and use it as a context. So it means that you can ask some follow up questions or add some details
without repeating everything again. And if you want to ask totally different questions or
implement a new functionality, I always recommend you to create a new chat. And so it will
be more clear to cascade. So you won't be messed with the old context. Also, when you have a
new chat, you also see a pass conversations right here. So you can also delete some conversations.
Another nice feature is voice input. You can use it to interact with cascade. So in its current
form, it can transcribe your speech the text. Like when you click on it, it's ask the allowance
like that you can use it from your operation system. And then you can record the message.
Okay. And also there is a button add context. You can add some mentions, workflows and images,
but will cover this functionality in separate lessons in detail. Okay, I hope it was
useful for you and see you in the next lesson.